Ebuka Odini

ebukaodini@gmail.com / +2349093590559 / 39, Aliu Bisiriyu Street, Lagos, Lagos

Summary

Software Engineer with +6 years of professional experience building web and mobile applications with Node, React, PHP and Flutter.

Blending the art of design and logic with skill of programming to deliver engaging user experience through efficient website development, proactive feature optimization and also follows best practices to improve product quality.

Loves team work and collaboration.

Experience

Full Stack Engineer

Tensei • Lagos, Lagos 10/2021 - Present

Software Engineer (Contract)

Spicy Guitar Academy • Lagos, Lagos 02/2021 - 10/2021

- Designed the website update on Figma.
- Developed the updated website.
- Integrated mutilple payment services into the mobile application
- Built the web version of the mobile application

Software Engineer (Contract)

Sports Fans Club • Lagos, Lagos 11/2019 - 03/2021

- Developed the frontend application for both customers and administrators.
- Developed the backend API for integrating with the frontend.
- Integrated payment and other third party APIs into the application.

Software Engineer

Mira Technologies Ltd. • Lagos, Lagos 11/2019 - 03/2021

- Sysbanker EE
 - Developed the backend APIs of the application.
 - Developed some frontend features in the application.
 - Deployed and maintained the application.
 - Integrated the application with other third party APIs.
- · Mira Bulk Mail
 - Developed the frontend application.
 - Developed the backend APIs for integrating with the frontend.
 - Deployed and mainitained the application.

Software Engineer (Contract)

- Developed the mobile application.
- Developed the administrator portal.
- Developed the backend APIs for integrating with the mobile application and the administrator portal.

Software Engineer Intern

Mira Technologies Ltd. • Lagos, Lagos 07/2018 - 03/2019

- HaboPay
 - Developed the backend APIs for the payment platform.
- · Habo Global Sanitary Wears
 - Developed the e-commerce backend API for the mobile application.
 - Developed the administrator portal to manage products, orders, payments and customer accounts.
- · Victory Gold Networks
 - Developed the website.
 - Developed the admin portal of the application.
 - Deployed and maintained the application.

Software Developer

Freelancer • Benin, Edo State 05/2017 - 08/2019

- Fully Fuzzy Linear Programming Problem Software
 - Developed the desktop application.
- Myscriptz
 - Developed the frontend application.
 - Developed the backend APIs to integrate with the frontend application.
 - Deployed the application.
- · Automated Loan Management System
 - Developed the desktop application.

Skills

| • | Javascript | • | React | • | Flutter |
|---|-------------------------------------|---|------------|---|---------|
| • | Redux | • | Typescript | • | Node.js |
| • | Next.js | • | РНР | • | Dart |
| • | HTML | • | Bootstrap | • | CSS |
| • | SCSS (Sassy Cascading Style Sheets) | • | Jquery | • | Mysql |
| • | MongoDB | • | RxDB | • | REST |
| • | Git | • | Docker | | AWS |
| • | Google Cloud Platform | • | Mocha | | Jest |
| | ΙΔV/Δ | | | | |

Education

Computer Science

University of Benin • Benin, Edo State 12/2019

- Graduated with a Second Class Honours (Upper Division)
- Winner in the 2019 App Contest, University of Benin.
- Developed a Project Validation and Filtering System for the department.

- Activities:
 - Conducted tutorial classes for my colleagues.Lead a team of 20 on a research project

Languages

• English • Yoruba • Igbo

Links

- <u>LinkedIn</u>
- Github
- **Twitter**
- <u>Portfolio</u>
- <u>Dev Blog</u>